visajourney.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy Policy - VisaJourney

**Privacy Policy  
****

Information Collection and Use

**  
VisaJourney is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from that disclosed in this statement and in the [Terms of Service](https://www.visajourney.com/forums/index.php?autocom=custom&page=terms). VisaJourney collects information from members at several different points on our website.  
**  
Registration**  
In order to use this website, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide some information (such as demographic information) but encouraged in order that we may provide a more personalized experience on our site. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on your hard drive containing information about your account with VisaJourney. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on this site. By setting a cookie on our site, you do not have to enter a password more than once, thereby saving time while browsing. You are not required to accept cookies to use this site although some features may not be available if you choose not to do so. In addition our advertisers may use cookies as well. For more information on our advertisers and their privacy policies see the Advertisers section below.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**Sharing**  
Aggregated demographic information may be shared with selected third party advertisers as proof of traffic volume and target audience for the purpose of securing advertising contracts on VisaJourney. The information is highly summarized and is in no way linked to individual visitors. 

**Advertising**  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these companies. We currently use [Google.com](https://www.google.com/), Media.net, Aol.com (Oath), Sovrn.com, Brealtime.com, RhythmOne.com and Pulsepoint.com for limited advertising. As third party vendors, these companies use cookies to serve ads on VisaJourney. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads based on users visiting VisaJourney and other sites on the Internet. Users may read how Google uses personalized data to provide targeted ads [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) and opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). [Media.net](https://www.media.net/privacy-policy), [Aol.com](https://policies.oath.com/us/en/oath/privacy/index.html), [Sovrn.com](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/), [Brealtime.com](https://www.brealtime.com/privacy-policy/), [RhythmOne.com](https://www.rhythmone.com/privacy-policy) and [Pulsepoint.com](https://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy) also use cookies to enable ad serving based on users visiting VisaJourney and other sites on the Internet. Their privacy policies and opt-out features have been linked to, by company name, for your convenience. You are ecouraged to read the noted privacy policies and may also visit the [NAI Opt-Out](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) page for additional options.

**Analytics**  
We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, what their device type is, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google’s ability to capture, use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy), which also includes opt-out information. You are ecouraged to read the noted privacy policy. 

**Spam Defense**  
We utilize [IPS Spam Defense Service](https://invisioncommunity.com/features/spam) to determine the likelihood a registering account is a spam source. As part of this service, during registration of a new account we pass the email address and IP address of the registering member to IPS Spam Defense Service to determine if the registering account is a spammer. The [Invision privacy policy](https://invisioncommunity.com/legal/privacy) describes their use of this information. You are ecouraged to read the noted privacy policy. 

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by VisaJourney. 

**Surveys & Contests**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and email address), and demographic information (such as town of residency, age level). 

**Security**  
VisaJourney takes every precaution to protect your information. The server on which this site resides is restricted to trusted personnel and contained in a secure data center. If you have any questions regarding the security at our website, you can contact us [here](https://www.visajourney.com/contact/). 

**Site and Service Updates**  
We occasionally send you site and service announcement updates. During registration members are permitted to opt-in to these mailings. Should you choose not to receive these announcements, VisaJourney can not be held responsible for notifying you of any any changes made to this policy. 

**Correcting/Updating Personal Information**  
Your personally identifiable information is always accessible by you and can be changed at any time by visiting your [profile page](https://www.visajourney.com/forums/index.php?app=core&module=usercp). If you no longer wish to be a member of VisaJourney, you should contact us [here](https://www.visajourney.com/contact/) to have your account disabled.

**Notification of Changes**  
Notification of changes to our privacy policy are sent to members by way of email announcements. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. During registration members are permitted to opt-in to administrator mailings. Should you choose not to receive these announcements, VisaJourney can not be held responsible for notifying you of any changes made to this policy.

 _last updated: May 24, 2018_ ****
